Liam Toby Buxton

Flat 45 Morgan House, Norwich, Norfolk, NR1 1QQ T: 07896033776 liambuxton91@gmail.com

Profile

I am a punctual, trust-worthy and intelligent professional with a background in photography and design. I have experience with both analog and digital photography. In my work I have made use of 35mm, medium format and some large format photography. Since my degree I have also become well versed in design tools such as Illustrator and InDesign, working on bespoke designs for customers with specific brand guidelines. I have also worked for local newspapers, creating designs for print, thinking creatively with the newspaper's brand and identity in mind.

Education

Northgate High School, Ipswich

GCSE

History - A
Geography - A
Resistant Materials - A
Science - A
Additional Science - A
Art - B
English Literature - B
English Literature - B
Mathematics - C
Spanish - C

A-Level

Photography - B
Psychology - B
English Literature - C
Geography (AS Level) - C
General Studies (AS Level) - C

University of Lincoln

BA (Hons) Contemporary Lens Media

During my time at Lincoln, I became confident using a wide range of photographic equipment such as medium format, large format, digital processes and post-production software such as Photoshop. I have also used video equipment and became familiar with editing processes and software such as Final Cut Pro and Premiere Pro.

Experience

Ipswich Town F.C. Catering Department (part-time), May 2008 – July 2009 B&Q Replen Team, Ipswich Ransomes Europark (part-time), Sept 2009 – Nov 2009 Sales Assistant, Fat Face, Lincoln/Ipswich (part-time), Sept 2009 – Sept 2011 I AM VIP Photography (part-time), Dec 2012 – Feb 2013 Customer Service and Amendments, Direct Line Group (full-time), July 2013 – Nov 2013 Photographer/Barman/Runner, 360 Bar Val Thorens (full-time), Feb 2014 – May 2014

Junior Designer/ Print Assistant, Leo Print (full-time), May 2014 – October 2014

I began my career at this position by taking photographs of products in a small light box that I had made using white card. I would then edit and upload the images to brochures and product guides. After proving myself at this task, I was kept on to become a Junior Designer and Print Production Assistant, using software including QuarkXPress, Adobe Illustrator, Photoshop and InDesign. I became confident with InDesign, using it in day-to-day tasks such as designing brochures, leaflets, newsletters, business cards, product labels, posters and other such products. I assisted with the print production of projects, ensuring the projects were printed to the client's specifications, taking utmost care with measurements and print quality to guarantee complete final products. Corresponding with each client was key; ensuring the happiness of the customer ensuring that their

corporate guidelines were being adhered to and that the expectations of the products were being met. I gained great confidence in this role and became very familiar with design software, typography, using PDF's as project proofs and understanding CMYK, RGB and Pantone colour schemes, also including finishing methods with the use of mechanical guillotines, embossing and laminating processes.

Page Designer, Archant (full-time), November 2014 – April 2017

I began my role with Archant designing daily newspaper titles for the East Anglian Daily Times and Ipswich Star. The core system used to track the status of pages in the design process is the CMS application, Citrix. I am very confident with this system having used it everyday in this role. I have made use of a vast library of styles within InDesign for fonts and objects, learning how to apply object and character styles whilst also being able to create master templates, folios and libraries of objects. Whether it is simple imagery to accompany a short report or larger pieces with more creative scope, I relished the challenge of creating bespoke designs with eyecatching imagery. I was soon moved to the Features Design team after I had proven my ability where I would design features for a much larger array of titles. In the Features team I had the responsibility of designing the motoring pages for the entirety of the Archant group and also property pages for a large number of the titles. I would often be given the opportunity to work within the Graphics Unit of the department creating infographics, maps and tables that would be used to accompany feature stories. Providing support to the Graphics Unit helped me to vastly improve my working knowledge of Illustrator whilst also allowing me to have creative freedom through bespoke design work that would add striking imagery to a news story.

Senior Designer, Archant (full-time), April 2017 - Present

Having proven myself over many various roles within the department of Editorial Production, I was promoted to the role of Senior Designer. This step in responsibility provided me with a move into the management team of the department. I was moved from Features Design to the Editorial Production team for the weekly and daily newspaper titles for distribution in Norfolk, Suffolk, London, Cambridge, Hertfordshire, Kent and the South West. The team produces 45 titles a week designing over 2,500 pages in that time period. As a Senior Designer it was within my responsibilities to ensure that the team was as efficient as possible and that communication with various offices around the country was just as efficient and concise. As a Senior Designer I would often take on design work that needed an experienced touch or work that had increased monetary potential with the inclusion of adverts and potential photo-sales. My time in this role helped me to understand the need to work efficiently with numerous deadlines as I took on work that others may be have been hesitant to undertake. I took well to the management aspect of the position and stepped in many times as acting Team Leader to oversee the team of 12 designers. Due to workload reorganisations I was reassigned to a team that solely designed the four daily titles. I became the lead Senior Designer for the Dailies Design team producing the Eastern Daily Press, Norwich Evening News, East Anglian Daily Times and the Ipswich Star for Norfolk and Suffolk. As these titles carried large monetary value and needed great attention to detail it was imperative that these titles had the best designers and I felt very proud to be the lead Senior Designer in such an established team of creative individuals.

References

Mrs. Denise Stocker Leo Print Ltd. Berewyk Hall Court, Bures Road, White Colne, Colchester, Essex, CO6 2QB 08456 581058

Le-Anne Burman Dailies Design Manager, Archant Prospect House, Rouen Road, NR1 1RE 07766738123